<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-02-09T12:47:06+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Contenttool - Smartest tools for content professionals</title><subtitle>Contenttools.io provides smartest tools for day to day usage by content professionals.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Importance of unique content in seo, and how paraphrasing tool can help</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/importance-of-unique-content-in-seo-and-how-paraphrasing-tool-can-help" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Importance of unique content in seo, and how paraphrasing tool can help" /><published>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/importance-of-unique-content-in-seo-and-how-paraphrasing-tool-can-help</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/importance-of-unique-content-in-seo-and-how-paraphrasing-tool-can-help">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/seoo.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
Paraphrasing tools are fundamental and helpful for SEO. Let us analyse how this tool can help. A paraphrasing tool, also called a writer’s re-writing tool is utilized to change any content in order to spare time as well as elude copyright issues. This tool is used effectively by businesses involved in web based composition work. When you are in an employment where new articles need to be published every now and then, this tool comes in very handy.
Now let us take a look at the significance of paraphrasing tools in SEO . The term SEO (Search Engine Optimization) implies building a unique technique to rank your site or your keyword on the top in web search tools like Google. Distribution of good content is one of the unique imperatives of this feature. The rethinking/ paraphrasing tool allows you to produce great content for your site. The best thing about utilizing these free rewriting tools is that you will get counterfeit free pass content. Counterfeit or plagiarized content is indeed troublesome. Paraphrasing tools are useful in the context of pupils as well. Plagiarism is now a crime and is being demotivated by most organizations. According to an independent survey more than 25% of the content found on the internet is plagiarized. At some point the readers will realize that your website and work do not have the potential to reproduce anything new and condemn you for the act. Students reproducing content and assignments using these tools, have the chance to score better than ones who use plagiarized content. This powerful and easy to use tool could also be beneficial for teachers.
Some bloggers or content writers often have to write a large amount of content and they avail the service of these re-writing tools, in order to save time. Physically editing large content can indeed be time consuming as well as quite tiresome and using these re writing tools can make your task manageable and easy.
While using these paraphrasing tools, you quickly get prompted by a vast number of synonymous words that you could use in your content to give it a unique look. Since valuable content generation is important to many marketers and digital bloggers, these re-writing tools could assist you in delivering top notch content therefore improving your online presence.
There are many free paraphrasing tools available online. All you need to do is to pick a tool as per your requirement and just upload the contents that require re writing. Let us take a look at some of the key benefits of using paraphrasing tools:
&lt;strong&gt;Increase Readibility&lt;/strong&gt;
According to the SEO experts at Yoast, &lt;a href=&quot;https://yoast.com/does-readability-rank/&quot;&gt;search engines love readable text&lt;/a&gt;. Using easy-to-understand copy can improve UX, reduce bounce rates, and help those using voice search. If writing in plain English doesn’t come naturally to you, try a paraphrasing tool like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.outwrite.com/paraphrasing?utm_source=quora&amp;amp;utm_medium=answer&amp;amp;utm_content=SEO&quot;&gt;Outwrite&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;strong&gt;Better reader engagement&lt;/strong&gt;
Google states that creating &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/7451184?hl=en&quot;&gt;useful and compelling content&lt;/a&gt; is the most important factor for SEO. For example the paraphrasing tools can assist you with active and passive voice detection in your sentences. Improvising your sentence formation can direct more readers to your content.
&lt;strong&gt;Addition of synonyms&lt;/strong&gt;
You can keep Google and your users happy by incorporating synonyms in your sentences. Some of the paraphrasing tools come with inbuilt synonym generators and these pop up when you are re phrasing your content on their website.
&lt;strong&gt;Improving originality&lt;/strong&gt;
Writing unique content is the best way to improve your SEO. Paraphrasing tools can help you to write the original ideas in a better way, without changing the core meaning of the sentence. You can utilize the services of plagiarism checkers as well in order to be doubly sure that you are providing your readers with well written and intriguing content.
&lt;strong&gt;Forming meta descriptions&lt;/strong&gt;
If you need help in writing descriptions some of the paraphrasing tools can assist you with these too. They will take your whole article and create a precise and summarized article.
&lt;strong&gt;Why are writers hired by companies?&lt;/strong&gt;
Most companies hire professional content writers and bloggers due to their creative inclination. Due to the creativity in writing, adding anything new will increase the visibility of the writers and bring their work under the limelight. As a writer you have the creative freedom to create unique content. However, when writing content for specific clients writers must keep in mind not to go astray from the topics . Content writing is a unique part of digital strategy for various marketing companies. You need well written and without it your SEO strategy is incomplete.
Creating high quality content is the need of every website and it plays an important role in building an image in front of the audiences. But, creation of top notch content is not a child’s play and requires a thorough command over the language. Since paraphrasing is all about creativity and aesthetics, do not rush to write your content. There is no limit to the magic you can create by using basic paraphrasing tools. It is true that you can create unique content with these tools. Being a content writer or a website manager, you may very well be aware how expensive it can be to obtain the services of a high quality content writer. This is when a paraphrasing tool comes into the scenario and with its quick generation of fruitful paraphrasing it is economical as well as time saving facility. However, one must be very careful to revise the content before they are being published because sometimes the replaced synonyms or sentences make no sense to the reader. This will create a negative impact on your work or website.
&lt;strong&gt;How to use SmallSEOtools?&lt;/strong&gt;
1.At the top of the web page you will find an enter text box where you need to paste the content you want to ideally rephrase.
2. The next step after you have uploaded the content is to click on the paraphrase button.
3.This paraphrasing tool will take a few seconds before it generates the content for you.
4.The results will contain the highlighted words which have replaced the original words.
This efficient tool allows you to quickly rephrase a 2000 word content pretty quick. There is no limitations when it comes to wording. These advanced services are absolutely free of cost. The website does not track or store any of your content and hence this tool is quite safe to be used.
We can therefore conclude that paraphrasing tools are essential for SEO , it can provide you with a good ranking in search engines and one must use it wisely. This is pretty much everything you need to know about paraphrasing tools and its effect on SEO.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ankita</name></author><summary type="html">Paraphrasing tools are fundamental and helpful for SEO. Let us analyse how this tool can help. A paraphrasing tool, also called a writer’s re-writing tool is utilized to change any content in order to spare time as well as elude copyright issues. This tool is used effectively by businesses involved in web based composition work. When you are in an employment where new articles need to be published every now and then, this tool comes in very handy. Now let us take a look at the significance of paraphrasing tools in SEO . The term SEO (Search Engine Optimization) implies building a unique technique to rank your site or your keyword on the top in web search tools like Google. Distribution of good content is one of the unique imperatives of this feature. The rethinking/ paraphrasing tool allows you to produce great content for your site. The best thing about utilizing these free rewriting tools is that you will get counterfeit free pass content. Counterfeit or plagiarized content is indeed troublesome. Paraphrasing tools are useful in the context of pupils as well. Plagiarism is now a crime and is being demotivated by most organizations. According to an independent survey more than 25% of the content found on the internet is plagiarized. At some point the readers will realize that your website and work do not have the potential to reproduce anything new and condemn you for the act. Students reproducing content and assignments using these tools, have the chance to score better than ones who use plagiarized content. This powerful and easy to use tool could also be beneficial for teachers. Some bloggers or content writers often have to write a large amount of content and they avail the service of these re-writing tools, in order to save time. Physically editing large content can indeed be time consuming as well as quite tiresome and using these re writing tools can make your task manageable and easy. While using these paraphrasing tools, you quickly get prompted by a vast number of synonymous words that you could use in your content to give it a unique look. Since valuable content generation is important to many marketers and digital bloggers, these re-writing tools could assist you in delivering top notch content therefore improving your online presence. There are many free paraphrasing tools available online. All you need to do is to pick a tool as per your requirement and just upload the contents that require re writing. Let us take a look at some of the key benefits of using paraphrasing tools: Increase Readibility According to the SEO experts at Yoast, search engines love readable text. Using easy-to-understand copy can improve UX, reduce bounce rates, and help those using voice search. If writing in plain English doesn’t come naturally to you, try a paraphrasing tool like Outwrite. Better reader engagement Google states that creating useful and compelling content is the most important factor for SEO. For example the paraphrasing tools can assist you with active and passive voice detection in your sentences. Improvising your sentence formation can direct more readers to your content. Addition of synonyms You can keep Google and your users happy by incorporating synonyms in your sentences. Some of the paraphrasing tools come with inbuilt synonym generators and these pop up when you are re phrasing your content on their website. Improving originality Writing unique content is the best way to improve your SEO. Paraphrasing tools can help you to write the original ideas in a better way, without changing the core meaning of the sentence. You can utilize the services of plagiarism checkers as well in order to be doubly sure that you are providing your readers with well written and intriguing content. Forming meta descriptions If you need help in writing descriptions some of the paraphrasing tools can assist you with these too. They will take your whole article and create a precise and summarized article. Why are writers hired by companies? Most companies hire professional content writers and bloggers due to their creative inclination. Due to the creativity in writing, adding anything new will increase the visibility of the writers and bring their work under the limelight. As a writer you have the creative freedom to create unique content. However, when writing content for specific clients writers must keep in mind not to go astray from the topics . Content writing is a unique part of digital strategy for various marketing companies. You need well written and without it your SEO strategy is incomplete. Creating high quality content is the need of every website and it plays an important role in building an image in front of the audiences. But, creation of top notch content is not a child’s play and requires a thorough command over the language. Since paraphrasing is all about creativity and aesthetics, do not rush to write your content. There is no limit to the magic you can create by using basic paraphrasing tools. It is true that you can create unique content with these tools. Being a content writer or a website manager, you may very well be aware how expensive it can be to obtain the services of a high quality content writer. This is when a paraphrasing tool comes into the scenario and with its quick generation of fruitful paraphrasing it is economical as well as time saving facility. However, one must be very careful to revise the content before they are being published because sometimes the replaced synonyms or sentences make no sense to the reader. This will create a negative impact on your work or website. How to use SmallSEOtools? 1.At the top of the web page you will find an enter text box where you need to paste the content you want to ideally rephrase. 2. The next step after you have uploaded the content is to click on the paraphrase button. 3.This paraphrasing tool will take a few seconds before it generates the content for you. 4.The results will contain the highlighted words which have replaced the original words. This efficient tool allows you to quickly rephrase a 2000 word content pretty quick. There is no limitations when it comes to wording. These advanced services are absolutely free of cost. The website does not track or store any of your content and hence this tool is quite safe to be used. We can therefore conclude that paraphrasing tools are essential for SEO , it can provide you with a good ranking in search engines and one must use it wisely. This is pretty much everything you need to know about paraphrasing tools and its effect on SEO.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Free sentence translation tools which you can use</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/cool/free-sentence-translation-tools-which-you-can-use" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Free sentence translation tools which you can use" /><published>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/cool/free-sentence-translation-tools-which-you-can-use</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/cool/free-sentence-translation-tools-which-you-can-use">&lt;p&gt;When you want to translate a word or a sentence into other foriegn languages , you probably think of using a dictionary or ask a friend who is well adept at the language. Sentences translation is a humongous task and most people face issues dealing with it. Sentence translators are effective and easy to use tools and have been developed after extensive research.While some of these sentence translators speak the words and sentences aloud, and others simply pop up with the translated text. While these online smart tools cannot replace the proficiency of human translators, these are still handy for those looking at quick solutions. In this post, we will share with you some of the effective translation tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you want to translate a word or a sentence into other foreign languages , you probably think of using a dictionary or ask a friend who is well adept at the language. Sentences translation is a humongous task and most people face issues dealing with it. Sentence translators are effective and easy to use tools and have been developed after extensive research. While some of these sentence translators speak the words and sentences aloud, and others simply pop up with the translated text. While these online smart tools cannot replace the proficiency of human translators, these are still handy for those looking at quick solutions. In this post, we will share with you some of the effective translation tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/translate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=google+translate&amp;amp;rlz=1C1RLNS_enIN842IN842&amp;amp;oq=Google+translate&amp;amp;aqs=chrome.0.0i131i433i457j0l2j0i433l3j0i131i433j69i64.335j0j4&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&quot;&gt;Google translate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google translate is the most popular and free to use tool that effectively translated words and sentences quickly into any other languages. Due to its advanced algorithm it quickly translates the sentences from the input boxes to output boxes instantly. On google translate, you also have a translate read back which allows you to teach yourself a language. This comes in handy when tourists want to travel to places where foreign languages one is not accustomed are spoken. Not only that, Google translate also provides you with dictionary type of language learning and you can see the meanings of the words translated along with examples of translated sentences. Plus, should you require further assistance you can reach out to the translate communities to verify the accuracy of what you have translated. No matter how much the length of your content is, Google translate can always assist you in translating it. It also allows you to copy, share and save the translate content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, a word of advice for those looking to translate professional documents with highly sensitive data, there could be some inaccuracies. Therefore double check your translated documents for business needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bing.com/translator&quot;&gt;.Bing Microsoft Translator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This online instantly translates phrases and sentences into any language you prefer. If your microphone is enable, you could also speak aloud the word, phrases or sentences that you want to translate. Further, you can also hear aloud the translated copy and could also share it on the web. Unlike Google translate, that offers more than 100 language translation, Bing Microsoft Translator offers to translate upto 50 languages and 5000 characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deepl.com/en/translator&quot;&gt;Deepl Translate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another free translator and you could translate upto 12 languages using this tool. This tool applies machine learning in order to produce closer to accuracy translated content which is a thumbs up factor when compared to other similar translating tools available on the web. Deepl Translate also offers definitions and options for automatic sentence completion. You can copy , share, save the file. If you want more details of a word, all you require is to double click it and a dropdown box will appear with all the definitions and examples of how the language is used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.translatedict.com/&quot;&gt;Translatedict&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Translatedict is a free online that translates words, sentences or phrases in upto 51 languages. It is not as user friendly to use as the above mentioned tools, but this tool also allows you to translate loud and copy the translate output. You can also use the help of voice translator. If you require professional assistance, you could fill their form and receive the quotes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;a href=&quot;https://translate.yandex.com/&quot;&gt;Yandex Translate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yandex doesn’t only translate the words , phrases and sentences it also additionally translates images and websites too for 99 languages. It is a simple tool and very efficient. If you upload an image for translation, you can effectively swap the same image and generate translated image output without the need of uploading new images everytime. It also supports up to 10,000 characters, voice input and output, offers predictive typing, a dictionary with transcription, pronunciation, examples for usage of the word or phrase, and suggests fixes for bad translations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6.&lt;a href=&quot;https://translation.babylon-software.com/&quot;&gt;Babylon Online translator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a leading provider in language translation services with over two decades of experience in the field of dictionary and thesaurus. Its online translation service offers an all in one platform from which you can translate single words, full sentences, find antonyms as well as synonym. Its database has more than 1700 thesaurus, glossaries, lexicon and encyclopedia covering a wide range of subjects and allows you to translate more than 77 languages. The best part is that you can download this tool and save it on your desktop and use it effectively to translate your documents. If you want professional assistance, simply apply for human translator services and you will be provided with quotations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reverso.net/text_translation.aspx?lang=EN&quot;&gt;Reverso&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an easy to use tool that automatically translates your content without the need to even press any translate content button. It also conjugates verbs in all modes and tenses in 13 different languages. Its integrated language features include natural-sounding, accurate translations using Neural Machine Translation (NMT), a spell-checker for higher quality translation, integrated dictionaries to fine-tune translations, synonyms, and examples in context. Also, you could improvise on your language learning skills by listening to how the texts are pronounced by native speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.noslang.com/&quot;&gt;Internet Slang Translator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This online translator tool allows you to allows you to enter improper of informal text in the content box. If you’re new to some internet terms,and want to understand what is being talked about on the web, this tool is for you. It translates common internet lingo to English so you won’t get other languages if you want slang in a foreign language translated into another language you can understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.online-translator.com/&quot;&gt;PROMPT Online Translator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free online tool that automatically detects the languages and translate them in upto 20 different languages. This tool uses neural, analytical, statistical, and hybrid translation technologies. There’s also a Word Forms section with all verb tenses in five main languages: English, French, Spanish, German, and Russian, and a Contexts section that helps you find examples of phrases or words in different contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.translate.com/&quot;&gt;Translate.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to translate work documents, emails or sections of text , Translate.com offers more than 90 language pairs to choose from. Like other online translation tools, you can use voice commands and generate read aloud sentences , copy and download them for further usage. Since this tool uses machine translation algorithms its translated phrases are near to accuracy. If you want to get your translated content verified, there are more than 30,000 verified translators who take up the meticulous task of verifying documents for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/dhanyawad.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ankita</name></author><category term="cool" /><summary type="html">When you want to translate a word or a sentence into other foriegn languages , you probably think of using a dictionary or ask a friend who is well adept at the language. Sentences translation is a humongous task and most people face issues dealing with it. Sentence translators are effective and easy to use tools and have been developed after extensive research.While some of these sentence translators speak the words and sentences aloud, and others simply pop up with the translated text. While these online smart tools cannot replace the proficiency of human translators, these are still handy for those looking at quick solutions. In this post, we will share with you some of the effective translation tools.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/output-8.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/output-8.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Manual or automated translation ? Top examples where automates translation fails for Indian languages</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/manual-or-automated-translation-x-examples-where-automates-translation-fails-for-indian-languages" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Manual or automated translation ? Top examples where automates translation fails for Indian languages" /><published>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/manual-or-automated-translation-x-examples-where-automates-translation-fails-for-indian-languages</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/manual-or-automated-translation-x-examples-where-automates-translation-fails-for-indian-languages">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/lastt.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/gg.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology and internet services were created in order to surpass the communication barriers across the globe . Even then we have not been able to fully break the barriers of languages. Scientists and developers all over spend countless hours as well as resources in order to improve the robotic achievements of language translation activity. For example, in order to provide their users with new experiences, &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.twitter.com/es/using-twitter/translate-tweets&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/help/509936952489634?helpref=search&amp;amp;sr=4&amp;amp;query=traducci%C3%B3n&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; recently added translations that allow messages to be transformed into more than 40 languages when sent or received from their web pages or mobile applications. Google has also announced the development of ‘AutoML Translation’ as a way of improving the interpretative abilities of its translator in 27 dialects. The latest step forward for artificial intelligence is &lt;a href=&quot;https://insidebigdata.com/2018/09/14/neural-attention-please-attention-models-can-work/&quot;&gt;Neuro-Linguistic Programming&lt;/a&gt;, a technology that stimulates the human brain and tries to capture the meaning of phrases and words in their context in order to adapt them into a new language (Source: Cultureconnection.com).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still in the process of generating 100% artificial intelligence accuracy and larger establishments do not fully trust automatic machine and tool language translation and still hire professional human language translators for the task.There is no actual threat to the profession of several professional translators as the service provided by the machine are quite different from manual ones. Both the systems have their respective advantages as well as disadvantages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated vs Manual translation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/auto.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our country India is home to 122 languages out of which 22 are designated as official languages. The complexity of human languages make effective language translation a humongous task for tool developers. Although this seems quite a task still its importance is many as there has been increased demand in providing digitized translated content. Few parts of the globe has the need to generate translation tools in so many different languages, as is required in the Indian subcontinent. The top six languages spoken in India are Hindi, Bengali, Telegu, Tamil, Marathi and Urdu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With automated translation platforms changing the way information is spread and allowing for global interaction, there is no doubt that these tools play an integral role in developing cross-country communications, especially as they continue to improve. Online translation tools have increased and improved tenfold. In November of 2016, Google revealed a new version of Translate that employs a translation engine called &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.googleblog.com/2016/09/a-neural-network-for-machine.html&quot;&gt;Google Neural Machine Translation (GNMT)&lt;/a&gt;. This system translates complete sentences using an artificial neural network. It links digital “neurons” in several layers, each one feeding its output to the next layer—a method loosely modeled after the human brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, new Google Translate began by translating eight European languages to and from English and then expanded to Chinese, Arabic, Hebrew, Russian, and Vietnamese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has now extended neural translation to include nine Indian languages. No system can perfectly incorporate the efficiency of human translators therefore, there are still weaknesses to be addressed with the neural translation system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.transperfect.com/blog/why-automated-translation-cannot-replace-humans&quot;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt;, users recently found that typing variations of the Latin text placeholder “Lorem Ipsum” into Google Translate yielded random English phrases. In all lowercase, “lorem ipsum” produced “China.” Capitalized correctly (“Lorem Ipsum”) became “NATO.” In all lowercase “lorem lorem” was “China’s Internet,” and so on. Internet users were perplexed by these cryptic messages, and soon after, Google had to correct these erroneous translations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at the deadly combinations of words to amusing errors caused by the use of free translation software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For larger companies like Coca Cola, translating and localizing the marketing message helps to build a strong local presence in each market. It so happened to Coca-Cola that when the brand decided to mix English and te reo Māori, New Zealand’s indigenous language translation fail happened. The combination translates into the native language as “Hello, Death.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only Microsoft but also Google Translate can create hilarious situations, such as receiving 15,000 eggs, after placing the wrong order on a local website!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we compare languages like French or Spanish with our Indian languages we find that all languages in India do not follow standard script and are very complex to input and still be grammatically correct. Even Devanagari script is very complex to be standardized for its multiple languages on an input device like a keyboard. For example,Amitabh Bachchan on KBC (Kaun Banega Crorepati) asks viewers a question for winning 1 Lac, users are expected to send SMS KBCQ followed by options A, B, C or D. He then quickly announces that SMS in local languages will be accepted. How many users you think will send the answer as (केबीसी क्यू क, ख, ग, घ) or any other local Indian languages?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenge of English to Indian Language - Syntactic Divergence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important structural difference in English and most of the Indian languages is the &lt;strong&gt;word order.&lt;/strong&gt; Since English uses the subject-verb-object order, and most of the Indian languages, primarily use subject-object-verb. Some of the Indian languages are of the nature of free word order. In the first example, we can see that word order “ate mango” becomes “mango ate” [&lt;em&gt;aama khaayaa&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Table 1:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example of Different Word Orders in English and Hindi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/last.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Source Journal of Intelligent Systems&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.degruyter.com/view/journals/jisys/28/3/jisys.28.issue-3.xml&quot;&gt;Volume 28: Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to read more about the challenges faced by developers in translation of English to Indian languages, you can refer to this &lt;a href=&quot;http://troindia.in/journal/ijcesr/vol3iss8/62-67.pdf&quot;&gt;journal.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scientists are constantly trying to improvise and recently we have seen since we have so many different languages clearly the researchers had to find a generalized approach that could be easily adapted from one language to another. It was in news recently that a multipart machine translation architecture, Sampark, is nearing its completion as the combined effort of 11 institutions led by the Language Technologies Research Center at the International Institute of Information Technology in Hyderabad (IIIT-H). Sampark combines both traditional rules- and dictionary-based algorithms with statistical machine learning, and will be rolled out to the public at &lt;a href=&quot;http://sampark.iiit.ac.in/&quot; title=&quot;http://sampark.iiit.ac.in/&quot;&gt;http://sampark.iiit.ac.in/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the improvement in machine learning, these examples show that machine learning cannot replace professional human interpreters when you plan global strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ankita</name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/output-7.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/output-7.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Plagiarism vs paraphrasing ?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/plagiarism-vs-paraphrasing" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plagiarism vs paraphrasing ?" /><published>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/plagiarism-vs-paraphrasing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/plagiarism-vs-paraphrasing">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plagiarism&lt;/strong&gt; is the act of using someone else’s work or ideas without crediting the original owner of the content and reproducing them as your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paraphrasing&lt;/strong&gt; a text means re writing a sentence or words without changing the original meaning of the same. The rewritten content consists of no duplicacy and hence is not plagiarized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Differences in terms of plagiarism vs paraphrasing&lt;/strong&gt; lie in the closeness of your text to original one. You can define plagiarism as word-for-word copying, which is forbidden. Paraphrasing helps present the same ideas but it doesn’t repeat what was already written somewhere. That’s a great way of relying on someone’s text but not copying it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An ethical writer takes great care to ensure that any paraphrased text is sufficiently modified to new writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let use see few examples of &lt;a href=&quot;https://edubirdie.com/blog/paraphrasing-vs-plagiarism&quot;&gt;paraphrasing&lt;/a&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/differences.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/differences-2.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s consider various paraphrased versions of the following material on the electrochemical properties of neurons (taken from &lt;a href=&quot;https://ori.hhs.gov/education/products/roig_st_johns/Examples%20of%20paraphrasing.html&quot;&gt;Martini &amp;amp; Bartholomew, 1997&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original content :&lt;/strong&gt; “Because the intracellular concentration of potassium ions is relatively high, potassium ions tend to diffuse out of the cell. This movement is driven by the concentration gradient for potassium ions. Similarly, the concentration gradient for sodium ions tends to promote their movement into the cell. However, the cell membrane is significantly more permeable to potassium ions than to sodium ions. As a result, potassium ions diffuse out of the cell faster than sodium ions enter the cytoplasm. The cell therefore experiences a net loss of positive charges, and as a result the interior of the cell membrane contains an excess of negative charges, primarily from negatively charged proteins.”¹ (p. 204).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paraphrased content :&lt;/strong&gt; A textbook of anatomy and physiology¹ reports that the concentration of potassium ions inside of the cell is relatively high and, consequently, some potassium tends to escape out of the cell. Just the opposite occurs with sodium ions. Their concentration outside of the cell causes sodium ions to cross the membrane into the cell, but they do so at a slower rate. According to these authors, this is because the permeability of the cell membrane is such that it favors the movement of potassium relative to sodium ions. Because the rate of crossing for potassium ions that exit the cell is higher than that for sodium ions that enter the cell, the inside portion of the cell is left with an overload of negatively charged particles, namely, proteins that contain a negative charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to thoroughly changing much of the language and some of the structure of the original paragraph, the paraphrase also indicates, that the ideas contained in the rewritten version were taken from another source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes in their attempts at paraphrasing, authors commit ‘near plagiarism’ because they fail to sufficiently modify the original text and thus, produce an inappropriately paraphrased version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inappropriate paraphrasing also happens sometimes by writers who are not adept at the technical know-how of the content. Therefore, the ability to properly paraphrase technical text depends in large part on the author’s conceptual understanding of the ideas being described and that author’s mastery and command of the technical language involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, inexperienced authors (e.g., students) have the greatest difficulty paraphrasing the advanced technical text often found in the primary literature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, practice a two step process of paraphrasing an article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, understand the basic structure of the sentence. Sentences can be simple, compound or simple compound. Once you have identified the sentence structure, you can reconstruct the sentences keeping in mind the active voice and passive voice formation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to distinguish your paraphrase from the original content is by working on the length of the sentences. Use short sentences and break them down into understandable and short sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, paraphrasing is not just about replacing right words here and there, it is about taking ideas and explaining them using various words in a manner where you are clearly able to express yourself to your reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let us now see the difference between plagiarism and paraphrasing correctly:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/differences-3.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/differences-4.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How to avoid plagiarism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quoting:&lt;/strong&gt; If you don’t want to alter the quotes, use quotation marks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summarizing:&lt;/strong&gt; Simplify the content in your own words. This means once you have understood the meaning of the passage simply write a condensed synopsis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paraphrasing:&lt;/strong&gt; If you want to use a source’s information, restate it in your own words through “new wording and phrasing in just as many words or slightly more words than the original.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What requires citation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time you use information that is not common knowledge , cite them appropriately. Suppose you are using someone else’s quotes, illustrations, facts and figures you must credit the source. These may require permission and some of these may be copyrighted content too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common knowledge exception&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Common knowledge need not be cited. So what exactly is common knowledge?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The reader would already be aware of it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s a widely accepted fact; for example, there are 60 seconds in a minute.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s accessible via common information sources.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It originates from folklore or a well-known story e.g. Ramayana, &lt;em&gt;Jataka&lt;/em&gt; tales.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s commonly acknowledged in your field and known by your audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to avoid charges of plagiarism you must not only document your sources correctly using an appropriate style guide (eg Harvard or Vancouver) , but you must also handle direct quotations and citations correctly. In order to ensure that your content is free from plagiarized content, use free plagiarism checker tools available for free online. It takes time to develop the skills required to paraphrase content . Thinking of developing writing as a profession? Remember to paraphrase well and use plagiarism tools when necessary. We have created a handy tool list for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Checkers of Plagiarism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.turnitin.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turnitin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.copyscape.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copyscape&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.grammarly.com/plagiarism-checker&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grammarly’s Plagiarism Checker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://plagiarismdetector.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plagiarism Detector&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.duplichecker.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DupliChecker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zotero.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zotero&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.refworks.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RefWorks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mendeley.com/?interaction_required=true&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mendeley&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://endnote.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EndNote&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools for writing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.grammarly.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grammarly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hemingwayapp.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hemingway&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://readable.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Readable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gingersoftware.com/pt&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ginger&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>ankita</name></author><summary type="html">Plagiarism is the act of using someone else’s work or ideas without crediting the original owner of the content and reproducing them as your own.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/ki.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/ki.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ways in which paraphrasing tools help content writers?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/ways-in-which-paraphrasing-tools-help-content-writers" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ways in which paraphrasing tools help content writers?" /><published>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/ways-in-which-paraphrasing-tools-help-content-writers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/ways-in-which-paraphrasing-tools-help-content-writers">&lt;p&gt;Technology these days is growing at a rapid pace and offering us creative innovations that make our lives more comforting. Everything that is introduced, has both a positive as well as negative effect and thoroughly depends on the intention of using it. If you find a way to use technology in a positive way , it will generate excellent results and if used in negative way, it will hamper your excellence. Today we will discuss about the paraphrasing tools and how it has helped content writers when used in an effective and wise manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paraphrasing tool has a growing popularity owing to its ease of usage and generation of valuable and unique content for bloggers and digital content writers. A plagiarized content hampers the hard work by bloggers and creative content writers and these get penalized .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paraphrasing tools like Prepostseo and rephrase-tool come in quite handy for those who are often writing enormous amounts of content and require to sieve out plagiarized content and rephrase them quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So what is a paraphrasing tool and why is it useful?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paraphrasing is a Greek word that means “An Additional Manner of Expression”.The paraphrasing tool is a useful tool that allows one to change certain words or rewrite whole sentences- at ease. There is no uncertainty that paraphrasing tools allow you to present unique content that are easier to read and understand. Let us understand the impact of paraphrasing tools using this example below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunita couldn’t go to class because it was raining outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paraphrase tool- It was raining outside. Sunita couldn’t go to class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paraphrasing tool essentially summarizes the sentences by changing the structure and adding in relevant synonyms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is a paraphrasing tool required?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These tools gives you the freedom to construct sentences in a specific way. For example you copied some sentences from a website, these paraphrasing tools then reconstruct these sentences without changing the meaning of the same, so that you are handed with uniquely written content one that is not plagiarized. This means you can create new works from works already created by others. These tools are majorly used by bloggers and writers who have to reproduce content in bulk and need to save time as well as money. Your work is created within a few seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages of paraphrasing for content writers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the top benefits for using these paraphrasing tools for writing your content:-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These tools are widely available and you can access them from anywhere.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using the tools you could make all kinds of amendments from sentences in a school project to documenting scientific essays.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These tools are free to be used hence saving your business money.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These tools provide you with new content within a few seconds therefore saving your time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Long written sentences can be cut short to understandable short sentences.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From spelling errors to syntactic errors, can be fixed using these tools.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These tools are very handy in detecting plagiarism.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rewording quotes are not always easy but these paraphrasing tools make it easy for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can summarize the whole content with this tool.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you want to write meta tags for a page, the meta tags need to be specific among many of its competitors. They would replace the present phrases with new synonyms to make meta tags search engine optimization handier.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Since content is the key to generate more reader views, the paraphrasing tools can assist budding writers in generating more views.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most bloggers and social media enthusiasts use these tools before publishing their content online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The developers who have built these tools have gone through massive amounts of research to understand plagiarism and paraphrasing in a very detailed way before the implementation of this tool. Since, paraphraser uses a giant database for its operation, hence there is no doubt, paraphrasing techniques refresh the sentences and statements with the purpose of making the core meaning clearer. Today these paraphrasing tools also support other languages apart from English therefore making it easily usable to other multilingual users. These tools assist professional writers, bloggers, students and researchers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How paraphrasing tool helps students?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing assignments can be quite challenging for students who are not in the habit of writing much. A lot of students have no idea how to filter the content and use them in a proper manner. Paraphrasing is another challenging aspect that most students struggle with. Plus, a lot of college students have no idea about the evils of plagiarism. Since assignments have a submission deadline and producing low quality content or not submitting on time has resulted in drop of grades for many students. When a student is working on some important assignment he or she should avoid having any unwanted distraction while working. Since paraphrasing is a time consuming task , we would like to highlight the benefits of using technology for this problem. Every paraphrasing tool has a purpose and one must be aware before using it. If you a student who has to take the task of working on more than 10,000 words of content, these tools are a boon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some students do not properly reword the copied words and this can be dangerous as these get caught in plagiarism checker. Thus taking such dangerous chances is definitely not a good idea. Some paraphrasing tools are hard to use and students do not want to waste their precious hours in trying to learn how to use it. When you open the link of the tool of your choice, insert the copied material into the text box. Once you have completed the uploading process the tool generator will provide you with the changed content. After that students can download their assignments and submit it without further delay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quillbot&lt;/strong&gt; is one of the best paraphrasing tools that can assist your writing in many ways. The final result of this tool will be 100% plagiarism free content. This tool smartly presents your content in such a way that neither plagiarism checker applications nor the human eye can catch it for duplication of content. This tool has the added perk of having a giant database for its operation. It picks up words from the database and inserts synonyms in the content as required. This is a tool where precision is at it’s best since the tool developers have thoroughly researched before creating this tool. The paraphrasing of Quillbot’s algorithm is quite complex. The tool comprehends your work in following ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understand the core meaning of your content and try to restructure it as close to the original content without changing the meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reshapes your sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make use of synonyms wherever possible and required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check for errors such as grammatical, spelling and even punctuations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have discussed how paraphrasing software can assist you in writing. Besides, paraphrasing tools are also completely safe in terms of SEO perspectives as they help to rank higher in the search results with better and fresh content.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ankita</name></author><summary type="html">Technology these days is growing at a rapid pace and offering us creative innovations that make our lives more comforting. Everything that is introduced, has both a positive as well as negative effect and thoroughly depends on the intention of using it. If you find a way to use technology in a positive way , it will generate excellent results and if used in negative way, it will hamper your excellence. Today we will discuss about the paraphrasing tools and how it has helped content writers when used in an effective and wise manner.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/si.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/si.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ways to become a good content writer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/ways-to-become-a-good-content-writer" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ways to become a good content writer" /><published>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/ways-to-become-a-good-content-writer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/ways-to-become-a-good-content-writer">&lt;p&gt;In simple words, content writing is all about wordplay. If you are someone who writes content that is reader friendly, creative and engaging, then you are a good content writer. For example, a new fashion designer has just launched her new website. If she wishes to showcase her distinction in the field and business, she will be doing so by producing content on her website that showcases her skills. Here the content will show her brand to the audience. Being a content writer comes with great perks. Depending on the nature of your work you have the incredible flexibility to either work from home or from office. But the job is not easy in nature and one must inculcate certain skills in order to be a published writer. As a content writer you will have to come with innovative ideas and the work could be anything from writing content for websites, blogs, technical or research papers. Before you take a pen, paper or even a laptop, you must know that writing great content is just not about writing what comes on your mind but generating content based on knowledge. Now that I have captured your attention let us take a look at what it takes to don the hat of a content writer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are seven skills sets one must emulate in order to become an unmatched writer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.Adaptibility&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might seem pretty obvious, but I have seen a lot of content that falls short of its task. It fails to engross the audience. For example, landing pages of a website should contain copy that is short and designed to persuade the reader to take action. Regarding tone, blog posts for a scientific equipment company targeting medical researchers will likely be much different from posts for an organic food shop targeting a wider range of health-conscious consumers. The more styles you adapt to the more adapted writer you become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.Research skills&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good research skills is the best way to generate high quality content. It is also important to find and include content only from trustworthy and reliable website and sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.Good understanding of SEO&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good content writers stay on top with SEO trends. It is important to understand how to craft SEO friendly titles and keywords thus keeping up with the latest Google trends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.Organizational skills&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping a calendar and knowing your deadlines is always the efficient and effective way. Turning on an important assignment late always sends a bad message to your clients. Prioritize your tasks and get them done promptly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5.Staying focused&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing is a creative action and requires constant focus. Therefore when you initiate a writing task make sure to remove all possible distractions from you side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6.Communication&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There could be tasks given to you that you are unfamiliar with. In order to deliver quality content it is important to communicate effectively with your clients and understand what they need from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7.Editing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First drafts are rarely perfect. Therefore in order to have a polished content one must be patient, disciplined with eye for detail to sieve all errors from the content before sending it for publishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now let’s understand the nitty gritty of how to become a good content writer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More or less everybody loves to write but very few of them take up professional writing and earn bread and butter from it. Many people are held back from utilizing their potential in creative writing as they suffer in self doubt. Therefore, we have enlisted some quick guiding tips that will enable you to work with improved proficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The scope of content writing is immense. With content writing there is no right or wrong. There are so many different types of content formats that you can specialise in ⁠— blog writing, SEO content writing, website content writing, copywriting, podcast scriptwriting, video scriptwriting, academic writing and many more. Each one comes with its own challenges and nuances. So, in the initial days, it is always better to narrow down your focus and navigate your areas of strength&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Huffington Post alone publishes nearly 2000 blog posts per day. So, irrespective of whether you are writing for a client or yourself, you need to make your content stand out. Here are a few tips to help you with this:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a content curation tool and try to understand the latest trends that are being written on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn to do content gap analysis by using various SEO tools.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You could also use free headline generators to get ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A content writer must do improved research in order to generate well written and summarized content. You could use tools like Evernote and EasyBib to write a drafted version of your content.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To be a successful content writer, you must understand the art of editing meticulously. A poorly drafted content with many errors will reduce your chances of retaining a client. Hence it is important you edit , proofread your content before publishing them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An analytical mind and good grasp over language is a must to be a successful writer. &lt;strong&gt;Let us look at some of the career options for you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freelancing is a great way to start your career. Companies are outsourcing their content writing to several independent writers these days. An abundant of such opportunities can be found on websites like Freelancer, Upwork and Fiverr.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you are a school or college going student, you could also try out an internship. I remember the cheer my first article brought which was published in The Hindustan Times when I was 19 years old.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blogging is another independent and creative way to explore. Setting up your blog is free and since no qualifications are required you are free to write at your own pace. You only require a unique style of writing that resonates with the choices of your audience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a professional addition to your career, you could possibly explore various certification courses in writing. From Search Engine Optimization to Content Management System, these certifications teach everything. Such courses improve your writing skills and also competence in the market. There are a number of courses available in India and abroad which are both online and offline-TBS The Brand Salon, Mumbai, Digital Academy 360, Bangalore or Udemy Content Writing Course (Online)&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tips for aspiring content writers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Read a lot&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Improve your networking&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Maintain a social media presence&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Strengthen your researching skills&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Broaden your horizon&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Successful content writers and bloggers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;1.Carol Tice&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;2.Heidi Cohen&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;3.Neil Patel&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;4.Brain Clark&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books on content writing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;1.Content Writing by Joseph Robinson&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;2.Everybody Writes by Ann Handley&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;3.The copywriter’s handbook by Robert W.Bly&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;4. Don’t make me think by Steve Krug.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, create an online writing portfolio. As a starter, it is always better to start applying for paid content writing gigs after you have a few content pieces and experience under your belt. This way, you will be able to showcase yourself better and convey to potential clients or recruiters that you can actually do the job, and do it well.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>ankita</name></author><summary type="html">In simple words, content writing is all about wordplay. If you are someone who writes content that is reader friendly, creative and engaging, then you are a good content writer. For example, a new fashion designer has just launched her new website. If she wishes to showcase her distinction in the field and business, she will be doing so by producing content on her website that showcases her skills. Here the content will show her brand to the audience. Being a content writer comes with great perks. Depending on the nature of your work you have the incredible flexibility to either work from home or from office. But the job is not easy in nature and one must inculcate certain skills in order to be a published writer. As a content writer you will have to come with innovative ideas and the work could be anything from writing content for websites, blogs, technical or research papers. Before you take a pen, paper or even a laptop, you must know that writing great content is just not about writing what comes on your mind but generating content based on knowledge. Now that I have captured your attention let us take a look at what it takes to don the hat of a content writer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/img/blog/blog-details-bg.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/img/blog/blog-details-bg.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Free content tools which every content writers should use</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/x-free-content-tools-which-every-content-writers-should-use" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Free content tools which every content writers should use" /><published>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/x-free-content-tools-which-every-content-writers-should-use</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/x-free-content-tools-which-every-content-writers-should-use">&lt;p&gt;Content writing is a challenging task and content writers should be flexible enough to wear multiple hats and serve as per the demands of the clients. Not only does your content writing requires it to be top notch, but once must also showcase proficiency in marketing, social media and also designing. But the single most perspective is to come out with valuable and unique ideas. Since the competition is intense, therefore in order to be visible to your potential clients you will need to post all the time. According to Orbitmedi.com ‘&lt;em&gt;about 23% out of 1,000 bloggers post 2 to 6 articles per week. And most of those articles are at least 500 to 1,000 words long’.&lt;/em&gt; In order to stay on top you can consider automating your task and this could help you to focus better and work distraction free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to simplify your choice, we have created a list of some free content writing tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/ideaflip-1.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/ideaflip2.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/idealip4.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/ideaflip5.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/idealip6.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/ideaflip-7.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/idea-flip-8.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/ideaflip-9.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/ideaflip-10.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ankita</name></author><summary type="html">Content writing is a challenging task and content writers should be flexible enough to wear multiple hats and serve as per the demands of the clients. Not only does your content writing requires it to be top notch, but once must also showcase proficiency in marketing, social media and also designing. But the single most perspective is to come out with valuable and unique ideas. Since the competition is intense, therefore in order to be visible to your potential clients you will need to post all the time. According to Orbitmedi.com ‘about 23% out of 1,000 bloggers post 2 to 6 articles per week. And most of those articles are at least 500 to 1,000 words long’. In order to stay on top you can consider automating your task and this could help you to focus better and work distraction free.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/l.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/l.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Best free Paraphrasing Tools which you can use</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/x-free-paraphrasing-tools-which-you-can-use" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best free Paraphrasing Tools which you can use" /><published>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/x-free-paraphrasing-tools-which-you-can-use</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/x-free-paraphrasing-tools-which-you-can-use">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a paraphrasing tool?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paraphrasing tools are tools that assist you with rephrasing , spinning or rewriting articles. These tools are mostly used by people who want to rewrite either a sentence or the whole article and give it a uniqueness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you a University student or a digital marketer? Digital marketers are probably aware about search engine optimization and search engine marketing- Content is the king. Incase your new website’s goal is to increase the traffic of viewers , you should be careful about Google penalizing your content if it is stolen from other websites. So be careful.At some point of time you will definitely need the services of paraphrasing tool. There are probably thousands of paraphrasing tools available in the market both free and paid services and it could be very difficult to choose which one would be best for you. Ofcourse it requires lot of time and effort to pick the write tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the reason we have listed some of the best paraphrasing tools available and also listed its features for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spinwriter&lt;/strong&gt;: This is a great online paraphrasing tool packed with features like stock photo integration, mass export and bulk content spinning. It also works well on a variety of devices. The spin writers unique feature allows you to rewrite or paraphrase your new article keeping your old article in the side view. This feature allows you to compare. You can also create more than 1000 variations of the same article.Available for just $77 a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cleverspinner&lt;/strong&gt;: You can create new and fresh content with the help of clever spinner. All you need to do is just copy the content and paste it in the clipboard and clever spinner will do the rest of the task! You don’t even need to hire a content writer for this task!. The pros of Clever Spinner is that it generates 100% unique articles for you. Rewriting complex sentences in record time has been made very easy. You could either use the 3 day free trial or buy this software for $9.90 / month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Best Spinner 4.0&lt;/strong&gt;: This is a really powerful paraphrasing tool. This software has the best built in English dictionary with hundreds of entries added by real users. On the bright side, this software also support fourteen other languages. The services of this software are available for $67 a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Word AI&lt;/strong&gt;: This software uses artificial intelligence in order to understand the text automatically rewriting your article with the same proficiency as any human writer! This tool first of all understands the meaning of the whole sentence and then paraphrases them for you delivering highly professional content. Other than English, it also supports languages like French, Spanish and Italian. The monthly plan for this tool is $49.95 / month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chimp Rewriter&lt;/strong&gt;: This online paraphrasing tool consists of advanced features like N spin, anchor text spin and random ordering. This product also uses artificial intelligence in order to understand the content and rephrase them in a language that is easily understandable. This tool supports almost all the language and also comes with in built thesauri. This tool comes at a price of $15/ month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**SpinnerChief 5:**This is the only rephrasing tool that comes with dual version - desktop and web. Both the version provides the same features. Spinner Edge uses latest cutting edge statistical replacement technology and part of speech analysis method to create content close to human quality of writing. This tool functions in a similar manner in which Google translate does. This tool has both free and paid versions- $273 is its one time yearly fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Quillbot:**This free paraphrasing tool offers fluency, standard, suggestive, creative, and concision to create a new text. Moreover, it comes with simple and easy to use interface that anyone can use it easily.Integrate this tool with MS Word to make writing more easy. The monthly pricing of this tool is $4.95/ month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Content Professor:**This tool utilizes a technique called article spinning, which is widely known among SEO professionals.With one click this tool rephrases and rewrites complex sentences in multiple ways. Since Content Professor has a large database of idioms, antonym, synonym and phrases this content comes quite handy for new developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEO Wagon article rewriter:&lt;/strong&gt; Using more than 500,000 synonyms within its dictionary, this article spinner engine suggests the writer with best words for the content so that the outcome can be human readable and engaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coder Duck:&lt;/strong&gt; Simply paste any article here and let their tool generate high-quality content within some seconds only. This is free to use tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although these paraphrasing tools are very handy and a great substitute to write error free and high level content, thus replacing the need for human writer involvement. We would still suggest you to double check and polish your content before you publish them. We hope this guide helped you to find the best and effective paraphrasing tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEO Magnifying paraphrasing tool:&lt;/strong&gt; Writing unique and creative content for your website is now made easy by the introduction of the SEO Magnifying paraphrasing tool. This can rewrite articles fast and free. Creation of rich content can now increase the traffic on your blog posts and websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caligoniat:&lt;/strong&gt; This tool is unique and different from the ones available in the market at present. This software has a handy control over thesaurus and synonyms that make your content more powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Word Flood:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a desktop application and a free to use tool. This tool works according to the demands of the professional writers and bloggers. Use this tool to polish your content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PrePost Seo:&lt;/strong&gt; Prepostseo offers the best paraphrasing online tool that rewrite article by replacing words with unique synonyms and produce plagiarism free result.With so many tools available these days on the internet it is incredibly hard to find a tool that is both reliable and efficient.You must have heard that good stuff has a costly price. However, that’s not the case with Prepostseo paraphrasing tool.It’s all free, easy, and handy to use for all kind of writers. If you are a student, teacher, or freelancer who writes on multiple niche and has to submit work in bulk within short span of time, Prepostseo comes in very handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goparaphrase.com:&lt;/strong&gt; It paraphrases the whole content in just a matter of a minute and gives useful and accurate results. It has a simplified user interface.This is the best professional paraphrasing tools that delivers quick results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generates unique, attractive and free to use content for users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ant Spinner&lt;/strong&gt;: Another free article rewriter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rewordify&lt;/strong&gt;: Like the other free websites, there just copy and paste your content to a text box.Unlike most free tools entering a captcha code isn’t necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complex Generator&lt;/strong&gt;: Complex generator is a free online tool for paraphrasing anything from sentences to complete articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/paraphrasing.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to use Article Spinner by SEO Tool Centre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are four steps to create unique/original content using STC article spinner PRO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step.1&lt;/strong&gt; Go to the website and copy and paste your favorite article/content that you want to spin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step.2&lt;/strong&gt; Choose your favorite language .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step.3&lt;/strong&gt; Click on the “Spin/Rewrite” button and wait for the suggestion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step.4&lt;/strong&gt; Replace your favorite keywords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step.5&lt;/strong&gt; Analyze the content for it’s uniqueness using best plagiarism detection tool.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ankita</name></author><summary type="html">What is a paraphrasing tool?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/r-2.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/r-2.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Top paid content tools which professional content writers should use</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/x-paid-content-tools-which-professional-content-writers-should-use" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Top paid content tools which professional content writers should use" /><published>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/x-paid-content-tools-which-professional-content-writers-should-use</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/x-paid-content-tools-which-professional-content-writers-should-use">&lt;p&gt;People these days want to read content that is unique. This is the best way to make your work visible as well as appreciated to your readers. Brands, marketers and bloggers are constantly trying out newer ways in order to generate unique and well written content. In order to write top notch content you could take assistance from paid content writing tools that most professional writers use. We have created a list for you to navigate your choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content creation and planning tools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/image1.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/image2.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/image3.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/image-4.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/image5.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/image-6.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ankita</name></author><summary type="html">People these days want to read content that is unique. This is the best way to make your work visible as well as appreciated to your readers. Brands, marketers and bloggers are constantly trying out newer ways in order to generate unique and well written content. In order to write top notch content you could take assistance from paid content writing tools that most professional writers use. We have created a list for you to navigate your choice.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/output-6.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/output-6.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">12 paid paraphrasing tools which you can consider</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/x-paid-paraphrasing-tools-which-you-can-consider" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="12 paid paraphrasing tools which you can consider" /><published>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/x-paid-paraphrasing-tools-which-you-can-consider</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/x-paid-paraphrasing-tools-which-you-can-consider">&lt;p&gt;Paraphrasing tools are highly in demand as they are being utilized widely by professionals involved in bulk content writing. These paraphrasing tools are pocket friendly as well as time saving and are essential for SEO and are being used by various digital marketing companies today who want to increase traffic to their websites. A well written content not only improves your digital presence but also builds a relation of trust between you and your clients. These tools help you in re writing large sentences or finding synonyms of words. Regardless of the fact that whether you use these tools for email and marketing, writing business reports or academic essays, the paraphrasing tools always generate great results. As a content writer if you want to improve your efficiency as well as showcase your website, consider using the paid services of the paraphrasing tools:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;strong&gt;Spinnerchief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These tools act as a sentence and synonym changer and produce easily understandable content without changing the meaning of the content. Spinnerchief is a great product which rewrites content at ease and produces plagiarism free result. With some many tools online which are both free as well as paid, we have gathered the best for you. You do not need to worry about refreshing your content as everything happens on cloud. This service comes at a price of $97 now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Quillbot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an excellent paraphrasing tool and generates content so unique that you will not find them on any other website! The site is easy to navigate. This tool is used massively by both students as well as professionals. The tool comes at a price of $79.95 annually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;strong&gt;WordAI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a programmed spinning instrument that totally revamps your content. With the help of WordAI, you can make propelled passage, and archive level twists dependent on its extraordinary comprehension of the substance. It understands words that have different meanings.This tool is quite pocket friendly and priced at $2 per 10,000 words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;strong&gt;CleverSpinner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/clver-spinner.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a web based article spinning and paraphrasing software tool with great features and capabilities. This tool uses artificial intelligence so that it can write as closely as human beings. This tool rewrites whole sentences and phrases with great ease. This is a user friendly tool. All you need to do is paste the article you want to spin in the content box and spin the content. This tool comes at a monthly price of $9.90.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;strong&gt;Spin Rewriter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spin Rewriter is a web based article spinning software released in 2011 by Aaron Sustar of SmileyTech Solutions. With several advanced features and functions, Spin Rewriter is currently one of the smarter content spinning software’s available and has received great reviews since its release. It uses algorithms to completely revise articles into a copy that no one has produced before. This tool rewrites paragraph, words and sentences. Make use of this tool with just one click- all you need to do is just paste the content you wish to be rewritten. These features comes at a price of $197 a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6.&lt;strong&gt;Chimp Rewriter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chimp Rewriter claims to be a complete content creation assistant rather than just a paraphrasing tool. This is an excellent and easy to use tool for those professionals who take content writing very seriously. This tool includes incredible features like N spin, anchor text spin, bulk rewriting directory, listing re ordering and random reordering. This is a smart and innovative tool that uses artificial intelligence technology in order to first understand the meaning of the content and tailor makes it to ensure that it is understandable. Since this product has in built thesauri it supports languages like English, Danish, Dutch, Italian, Slovenian, Portuguese and many more. It is integrated with content creation suits including GSA search engine ranker, RankWYz, WP robot, Ultimate demon and SEO content machine. Chimp Rewriter has two pricing one is monthly and another yearly. It also provides free 14 days trial service. The monthly price is $15 and the annual payment plan is $99.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7.&lt;strong&gt;SpinnerChief 6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of the finest paraphrasing tools available on the web and can produce bulk content in a matter of a few seconds. It specializes in generating 100% quality content with the precision that is easily understandable by everyone. This tool uses a new technology called Statistical Replacement Technology (SRT) which operates in a radically new manner by using the most appropriate statistical synonym for any word or phrase. The technology functioning is quite similar to what Google translate does. It is the only paraphrasing software which offers desktop and web versions of the software. You can save the data in any custom format or submit it to the website or blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has 2 basic plans namely Free version and Elite version. For Elite version, you have to $87 one-time fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Team Version pricing is also available based on the number of users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 (One-time Option) 3 Users $273, 5 Users $413, 10 Users $689&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 (Per Year) 3 Users, $122 , 5 Users $204, 10 Users $273&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8. &lt;strong&gt;The Best Spinner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tool quickly generates hundreds of content just with a click. This tool comes in with built in spelling and grammar checker as well. Priced at Basic plan $67/ year, Standard package (most popular) $127/ year, and Pro (best value) $297 / year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9.&lt;strong&gt;Paraphrasing services.org&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spinning software as it is often called is used to deal with everything from short sentences to whole articles and papers. The trouble is that these software programs do not understand the context in which words are being used not the complexity of the human language. They try to change individual words or short phrases for synonyms but the end result is often very poor indeed. This company therefore offers proficient human help. Some of the services offered by this company are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understand the original text from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make notes to highlight all of the points from the text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rewrite the text from the notes, not from the original text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compare the two to remove any unintentional duplication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proofread the text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provide any necessary citations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paraphrasing $8.79 per page&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summarizing $14.39 per page&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Editing $7.19 per page&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10.&lt;strong&gt;Rewriting services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From articles and assignment to lab reports and dissertation this paid service offers to check plagiarism and also paraphrases articles in a professional and efficient manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Services stated on their website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speedy updates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total security&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maximum uniqueness in content generation using fitting terms and phrases&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proper referencing and citation of articles&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Priced at $7.56 per 275 words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11.&lt;strong&gt;Rephraser.net Tool&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Priced at $24.99 per paraphrase this is another affordable and handy service for those who are looking to avail paraphrasing services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12.&lt;strong&gt;Content professor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/content-professor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It paraphrases the whole content in just a matter of a minute and gives useful and accurate results. Generates unique, attractive content for users. Some of the premium features include a change assistant feature, advanced spell checker technology, customizable duplicate content checker and integration with Copyscape and Plagium.The services are both free as well as paid. Priced at Quarterly: $9.99/mon and Monthly: $19.95/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tool you choose ultimately depends on what exactly you want to accomplish and how you are going to use the rewritten content.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ankita</name></author><summary type="html">Paraphrasing tools are highly in demand as they are being utilized widely by professionals involved in bulk content writing. These paraphrasing tools are pocket friendly as well as time saving and are essential for SEO and are being used by various digital marketing companies today who want to increase traffic to their websites. A well written content not only improves your digital presence but also builds a relation of trust between you and your clients. These tools help you in re writing large sentences or finding synonyms of words. Regardless of the fact that whether you use these tools for email and marketing, writing business reports or academic essays, the paraphrasing tools always generate great results. As a content writer if you want to improve your efficiency as well as showcase your website, consider using the paid services of the paraphrasing tools:</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/output-5.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/output-5.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>